SKILLS

- Active Directory
- Azure Active Directory
- Windows Server 2008-2019
- Windows Deployment Services
- Remote Desktop Services
- Windows (XP 10)
- Linux (Ubuntu, Debian, Fedora)
- MacOS & iOS
- Android
- Java
- HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- Python
- Computer Hardware
- Zoho Desk, Zendesk

EDUCATION

2019 - Present

University of Liverpool | *Liverpool* Computer Science (BSc)

2016 - 2018

Twyford CE High School

• Computer Science

• Government & Politics

• English Language (IGCSE)

• English Literature

• Additional Science

• Core Science

History

French

A-Levels

 EPQ (focussed on Encryption Ethics) Mathematics 2011 - 2016 Twyford CE High School GCSE 	B D
	Computer Science
Religious Education	A
 Mathematics 	Α

Joel Vivian

(+44) 07498626207 joel@jdvivian.co.uk

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a highly ambitious 2nd year computer science student at the University of Liverpool, with a desire to learn new skills and code new and exciting things. My previous experience is with in-person, phone, and remote IT support, both in the context of general IT support, as well as specific applications. I also have experience in helping in the IT recovery from a cyber-attack on a multinational company.

WORK HISTORY

09/2021 - Present

Liverpool Guild of Students

Student Staff Team Member - Venue Technical Staff

As part of the student tech staff, I help provide lighting and sound for different guild events, such as concerts and talks.

04/2019 - 09/2019

В

В

Α

В

В

В

C

C

Simpson Spence Young

Trainee First Line IT Support Technician

My primary role was to provide first-line support to brokers and other employees at the company. This was done both through the phone and in-person, to employees both in the London office that I was in, as well as offices internationally. I used Zoho Desk to manage and respond to tickets. As this was a small IT team, I also found myself performing other roles as well, such as building computers and servers, performing machine upgrades, learning, and eventually performing Active Directory maintenance and support. During my time in this role, I also helped the company recover from a cyber-attack and made several pieces of bespoke software for use by the IT team I worked within.

07/2018 - 09/2018

Egress Software Technologies

First Line Support Technician

During my time here I was part of the customer support team for the CJSM service, providing phone support to users of the service who were having issues. This involved guiding users on how to use the software, as well as performing actions such as password resets. I used Zendesk to manage and respond to tickets. On some occasions, I also served as a customer support technician for the Egress Switch software, primarily when service issues meant there was a high volume of customer support calls and emails.

As well as this, I also covered reception duties for an hour each day - acting as the face of the company to any visitors to the office, as well as those who called the general company number.

01/2014 - 01/2018

Twyford CE High School Tech Team

Member of The Technical Team

During my time in secondary school, I was a member of the in-house technical department. This meant running the sounds and visuals for school assemblies, as well as assisting with operating live events software and hardware during larger events, such as open evenings, parents evenings, and the yearly school production.

06/2015 - 06/2015

Egress Software Technologies

2 Weeks Work Experience

As part of my placement here, I rotated through various departments, including HR, IT Operations, Marketing, and Customer Support. This taught me valuable skills across several fields, including the types of IT issues that are encountered in a commercial environment, as well as skills in customer interaction through the Marketing and Customer Support teams.

2016

National Citizens Service

 Three weeks in which I learnt teamwork skills – working with a team to solve problems and puzzles, as well as management skills – planning and running a charity stool to raise money to get braille books in Hounslow Library, interacting with members of the public to help get them interested in the cause.

PERSONAL HOBBIES

In my own time, I enjoy experimenting with the software on my own electronics, rooting my own phone, as well as an Amazon Fire TV Stick (gen2), and using a CLI to send commands to my linux-based Bose Smart Speaker. As well as this, I like to code in my own time, working on projects to help me improve my programming skills. I also have a passion for computer hardware, building 2 desktop computers. Beyond computers, I have a passion for music, playing guitar (electric and acoustic), bass, and drums, and an interest in US and UK Politics.

REFERENCES

References are available on request.